(Watch on KonFlix.vip)
‎PREVIOUSLY ON ‎TATSUKI: TOO KIND FOR SCHOOL
She said that she likes the color gold.
But I wonder if she said that
with her parents in mind.
You need to go to cram school and study.
She loves playing the piano.
Mr. Tatsuki! It's about Nene…
Thanks for coming.
I don't know what to do anymore.
Don't come in here! Go away!
Sora!
Open the door, Sora!
I…
don't know what to do either.
What?
But…
I have to do something.
I'm sorry.
YUKANAI
SPRING, 2019
Hey,
let's get going or we'll be late.
Okay.
-Here, this is for you.
-Oh?
Wow.
-It's pretty.
-Right?
-Thanks.
-Okay, Dad, let's race.
But I'll get sand in my shoes.
Ready, start!
Hey.
Hold up!
Oh no!
Hey!
SUMMER, 2023
Hey…
What is it?
I want to take the entrance exam.
-What?
-Entrance exam?
Dad, you took it too, right?
I want to go to cram school.
Oh…
What do you think? It'll be tough
to start now, won't it?
But I don't regret taking the exam.
Okay.
If you're willing to do your best,
we'll fully support you.
I'll do my best.
Okay.
Summer is the make-or-break period
for entrance exams.
Train yourselves now
so that you can give your all next summer.
Yes, sir.
All right, try solving
the next question.
Once you finish, move onto the next…
154 DAYS UNTIL
THE JUNIOR HIGH SCHOOL ENTRANCE EXAMS
Hey, there.
What's the matter?
I barely passed the mock exam.
What?
GRADE - C
There's still time, so keep at it.
I'm tired.
You're the one who wanted to do this.
Yeah, but…
Once you get accepted into a school,
you can have all the fun you want.
Yeah.
HAPPY NEW YEAR
TOEI GAKUEN JUNIOR HIGH SCHOOL
ENTRANCE EXAM RESULTS
USERNAME
PASSWORD
Hurry up.
Hold on…
CONGRATULATIONS, YOU PASSED
-All right!
-Wow!
-I did it!
-Congrats!
I did it!
I guess Sora won't be
walking with us anymore, huh?
Since he's in junior high now.
And his school is far from here.
-Later.
-Yeah.
MID-TERM EXAM
What are you doing?
The concept this time
is a fountain pen that doesn't
interrupt the thought process.
YU
We branded this fountain pen,
um…
not solely for writing, but to accompany
you during periods of deep contemplation.
Hello?
Yeah?
What?
What? He was caught cheating?
Why did you cheat, of all things?
Is it hard to keep up with your studies?
You worked so hard to get in,
so why do something so stupid?
Hey,
say something.
Hey, Sora.
Sora.
SHUT UP
Since today is the 2nd of the month,
the second person on roll call
will solve this one. Which is…
Here.
Okay, Ukita. Come up here.
Let's break it down once,
like we did with the example equation.
-Look at your cheat sheet.
-That's too harsh.
-He'll never be able to solve that.
-Yeah, for sure.
Look, he's frozen.
You can go back to your seat.
-Hey!
-Ukita!
-You wanna fight?
Stop it!
Calm down, Ukita!
Hey!
-Hey.
-Yeah?
Sora is holed up in his room
and won't come out.
Why?
Apparently, he had a fight
with a friend at school yesterday.
That's it?
Hey, why aren't you coming out?
Sora, hiding out like that
isn't going to solve anything, you know?
Hey, let's talk together.
Are you listening?
-Sora.
-That's enough. Go to work.
Open the door.
Sora.
-Come out here.
-I don't want to!
Stop it, that's enough. Just stop!
Sora!
TWO WEEKS LATER
What about work?
I'll take the day off again.
Okay, thanks.
How long is this going to continue?
I'll think of something.
Bye.
ANY CHILD WITH SCHOOL REFUSAL CAN RETURN
TO SCHOOL - GUARANTEED 97% SUCCESS!
"REVIVAL!" A SPECIALIZED SUPPORT SERVICE
FOR SCHOOL REFUSAL
When did his school refusal begin?
I'm not sure yet
if it's exactly school refusal,
but it started about two weeks ago.
Two weeks, I see.
It's not too late.
Really?
It all started…
with the cheating?
I believe so.
That made it difficult for him
to go to school?
Yes.
If you follow our program as directed,
he should be able to return to school
in approximately three to four weeks.
Is that right?
Children are not to be blamed
for experiencing school refusal.
In other words,
the ones who need to change
are the parents.
What is it?
-What are you doing?
-You can have them if you go to school.
What?
Give it back to me.
IT ALL STARTS WITH PARENTS'
CHANGING THEIR MINDSET
The parents' mindset…
Aren't you taking this a bit too far?
It's all because
you keep spoiling him like that.
What? So it's my fault?
If he has his phone and games,
he won't feel the need to leave his room.
Hey, is this company really trustworthy?
We, the parents, need to make changes.
Are you listening to me?
Starting tomorrow,
I'll set a routine schedule for him.
Wake up.
-Get up.
-Stop it.
Hurry up.
Listen up, Sora.
You're capable of hard work, and you can
do anything if you put your mind to it.
Right?
So
let's get you back on a routine schedule.
My phone…
You don't need your smartphone,
games, or comics.
If you're not going to school,
study at home.
Got it?
You can have it back
once you go to school.
Crying won't solve anything.
Stop being so harsh.
Do what needs to be done.
Sora.
Put away your own dishes.
Hey, Sora!
OFFER PRAISE,
ESTABLISH A PROPER HOME ENVIRONMENT,
ENCOURAGE INDEPENDENCE, RETURN TO SCHOOL
Sora?
You're going to school?
I'll be off.
-Hey, Sora went to school!
-What?
Really?
I'm glad.
Didn't we have art class today?
Oh, did we? Let's hurry.
I'll go too.
ART
All right everyone, start sketching.
Okay.
Sora?
What are you doing?
Dad told you
that you can't use your phone, right?
I went to school, so it's fine.
Sora…
Give it to me. It's all right.
Just give it back to me.
Sora.
Give it back.
Give it back!
I'm home.
What?
What happened?
Sora.
Hey, Sora!
-Sora!
-Don't come in here!
Go away!
Why…
He was never the type
to do something like this.
-Open the door, Sora.
-Shut up!
Hey Sora.
Open the door.
MUNICIPAL GENERAL MEDICAL CENTER
Are you scolding him harshly,
or doing anything that might
make him feel cornered?
Well,
I am, of course, a little strict with him,
but it’s because I want him
to lead a disciplined life.
Right now, he might be feeling
intense stress at both school and home
to the point where he feels
he has nowhere left to turn.
For now, please prioritize
-your child's feelings.
-Huh?
That's really okay?
-His school refusal will never be solved--
-Sir.
Focus on giving the help he needs
right now.
Then what do you suggest I do right now?
Let's see.
How about I introduce you
to a certified psychologist?
No, thank you.
EXAM ROOM 2
I'll go home on my own.
Sora.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
No worries. Please go after him.
Thanks for helping.
I understand how you feel.
My son also went through a terrible
rebellious phase back in the day.
If you have time,
please come to this event.
LET'S TRY ART THERAPY!
-I see.
-I'll be going now. Bye.
FINDING YOUR INNER SELF
THROUGH ART THERAPY
Where were you?
Am I sick?
What do you mean?
I was at the hospital.
What?
Why did you take him to the hospital?
We went to a psychosomatic clinic.
I thought they might be able to figure out
what caused this.
Why?
What do you mean by "why"?
You didn't even consult with me,
and paid money to some shady company,
-and took him to a hospital--
-It's to help Sora.
It's not helping him at all!
Can't you see that he's getting worse?
I can't take this anymore.
I want you to stay away from him.
-What?
-I'm begging you.
FROM YU
DIVORCE FORM
YU UKITA
You're showing signs of depression.
Please do not overexert yourself at work,
and try to eliminate
environmental stressors
as much as possible.
Do you have any family members
that can provide support?
No.
I haven't drawn in so long,
I'm a little nervous.
Yeah, it's a bit nerve-wracking.
Thank you for coming today.
It's so nostalgic.
This was drawn using crayons.
Welcome.
Please come inside.
No, I'm all right.
Please come in.
You may not be very familiar
with the concept of art therapy,
but it is a therapeutic approach
in which you engage with your inner self
and sort through your feelings
with activities such as drawing
or working with clay.
And please be rest assured,
despite the name,
you do not need any artistic skills.
Are you relieved?
Today, please draw a landscape
that is memorable to you,
or perhaps the sky.
Please begin.
Please relax and enjoy drawing.
-What should I draw?
-Enjoy.
You painted a view of the sky by the sea.
Yes.
What kind of memories do you have here?
There's no specific "memory," but…
Are these footprints?
Yes.
You must've walked quite a distance.
I really felt like I was doing my best,
but it seems
I was just spinning my wheels…
Even the things I did
with my son's best interests at heart
turned out to be wrong.
I'm sorry.
No need to apologize.
You can talk about anything here.
What's the matter?
Both family and work
can be lost in an instant.
This…
is scenery I'll never get to see
ever again.
I'm sorry.
-No worries.
-Thanks.
Do you draw often, Mr. Tatsuki?
Yes. I studied design at university.
No wonder you're so good.
Do you draw too?
No, I specialize in psychology
and I'm terrible at drawing.
But art is very useful
when trying to confront oneself.
I see.
-Mr. Tatsuki.
-Yes?
Do you have time after this?
What?
YUKANAI
NOW ACCEPTING NEW STUDENTS
This way. Please come in.
Thank you.
Hey everyone.
-Hello.
This is the alternative school
that I founded.
-Alternative school?
-Yes.
I wanted to create a safe space
for children who,
for various reasons,
find it hard to attend school.
I see.
Oh, you're drawing.
Look at this.
You're so good.
-Really?
-Yeah.
-Look.
-How cute.
-Look at this.
-Isn't this funny?
That's cute.
This way.
Okay.
I'm thinking it'd be nice
to offer art therapy here
as a way to tie it in
with my own research.
I see.
Would you like to work here with me?
What?
You quit your other job, right?
Yeah, but…
You lost everything
triggered by the issue of school refusal,
and now you're at rock bottom, aren't you?
You're so brutally honest.
Are you good with games?
Not really.
But you can draw.
-I think you're suitable for this job.
-Um…
I'm very thankful for the offer,
but why me, we've only just met?
My intuition, I guess.
What?
-I'm first.
-No, it's me.
-It's my turn.
-Hey, hey.
-Let go.
You have to take turns.
-Or someone will get hurt.
-It's my turn.
Wow, that was consecutive.
Seiryu,
clean up after yourself.
Don't leave things out.
I didn't do that.
Huh?
Who wants to play in the courtyard?
-So, about this…
-Yeah?
Haruhi, Kurumi, wanna play?
-No, I'm okay.
-No thanks.
-Soya, let's play Mario Party.
-You're not going to play soccer?
No, Mr. Tatsuki is scary.
-Oh…
-Let's play games.
-Okay…
-I wanna play with you too.
Oh no, hold on.
That was close.
Watch out!
Mr. Tatsuki, are you all right?
Oh my god.
It's Café-Au-Lait Man!
No, he's a zombie.
You're right. He's a zombie.
-Café-Au-Lait Zombie.
-Hey, zombie.
A zombie! A zombie!
Who are you calling a zombie?
The zombie is here.
Peter Piper picked a peck
of pickled peppers…
Good morning.
What the…?
What?
What do you think?
Your hair color changed.
A makeover? That's nice.
You look like Super Saiyan.
-You're Super Saiyan!
-It's gross.
Who said it was gross?
The look suits you.
You look like a nice fairy.
Thank you.
-Mr. Tatsuki.
-Yeah?
I want to draw.
Okay.
But from now on,
you can just call me Tatsuki.
-Tatsuki, can we use the atelier?
-Of course.
-Let's go, everyone!
-Yeah.
Wait for me.
-Tatsuki.
-Yeah?
Not bad.
Shut up.
-Not bad.
Not bad.
-Enough already.
YUKANAI
YU
-Hello?
-Tatsuki…
Sora… Sora…
What about Sora?
Sora jumped.
What?
Hey there.
Hello.
I heard that Nene's situation
isn't looking good?
Yeah.
Is it okay if her grades keep dropping?
You need to go to cram school and study.
She loves playing the piano.
I hate playing the piano.
-Then why didn't you say so?
-There's no way I could.
If I do,
you and Dad will start fighting again.
I don't want things
to turn out like it did with Sora.
But I don't know what to do.
How were her parents doing?
They're very similar
to how I was back then.
As if their expectations and hopes
for their child have gone awry,
trapping them in a vicious cycle.
I see.
I went to the door of her room,
but I couldn't do anything,
and I just left.
Why don't we invite her parents here?
Invite them here?
There's some art therapy
I want to try out.
Of course, you’ll be doing it too.
This way, please.
Hello.
I'm Mikumo, the representative at Yukanai.
-Thank you for your help.
-Thank you for coming.
Why were we called here today?
We're all concerned about Nene,
but we can only imagine
that it's been a tremendous burden
on you two as well.
So we wanted to have you
spend some time relaxing today.
So we prepared this.
Please sit down.
Yes, please.
Thank you.
Does this have anything to do with Nene?
Yes.
Please bear with us
for just a little while.
This is a traditional dyeing
and transfer technique
called suminagashi.
I'll start by showing you how it's done.
Start by dropping
sumi ink onto the surface of the water.
And this is oil.
Mix the oil with the sumi ink.
You can swirl the sumi ink like this.
Once you're done with that,
you can gently shake
the surface of the water,
or you can blow on it as well.
Oh no,
it's not turning out the way I imagined.
Last but not least,
I'm going to place the paper in the water.
This is how it turned out.
Wow.
Shall we all try it as well?
Sure.
I'll give it a try.
Mrs. Tachibana, you're so good at this.
It's so pretty.
You're doing well too.
Oh no, don't go that way…
At first, I was trying to create a dragon,
but this is how it turned out.
I actually put in a bit too much sumi ink
right at the start,
so I decided to just utilize that
and simply go with the flow.
How did you like it?
Well,
I couldn't control it well enough,
so it was a bit frustrating.
And you, Mrs. Tamami?
It turned out completely differently
than I had imagined,
but that actually
made it all the more fun.
Mr. Yukio approached it with
a clear vision right from the start,
while Mrs. Tamami simply let
the ink take its course.
That contrast is quite fascinating.
How about you, Tatsuki?
With suminagashi,
once you drop the ink, there's no telling
how it's going to spread, huh?
Watching over those
unpredictable movements
is what makes this fun.
But
I guess I was trying to control things
to make it turn out the way I want.
You haven't seen
Nene's diamond art yet, have you?
No.
You mentioned
that she chose brown and pink
because she thought they were colors
that'd make us happy, right?
Yes.
At first, she didn't have the confidence
to choose the colors herself.
What about this foal?
At first it was made with a mix
of brown and pink,
because brown would make her dad happy,
and pink is her mom's favorite color.
But before she could show it to you guys,
she tried to destroy it.
But she brought it with her
to the Yukanai Camp.
I worked so hard to make it,
but I ended up destroying it.
And when she decided to work on it again,
she was finally able to tell me
her favorite color.
The truth is, my favorite color is blue.
As I listened closely,
I gradually began hearing the words
she couldn't bring herself to say
until then.
I see.
Perhaps
we were doing nothing but forcing
our own feelings and expectations
onto her.
Yeah.
We'll try once more
to see Nene eye to eye.
That's wonderful.
I think that's a great idea.
I actually have a suggestion
for the both of you.
NENE
We tried our hand at diamond art too.
The messy part was done by Dad.
Nene, please finish the rest.
NOW ACCEPTING NEW STUDENTS
Good morning Tatsuki.
Good morning.
I decided not to leave.
Huh?
All right!
What should I do today?
What's this?
That's called suminagashi.
-I see.
-Oh.
Do you want to try paper marbling?
What is that?
It's similar to suminagashi
but it uses color ink.
I want to try it.
Your style is so free and relaxed.
It's nice.
-Really?
-Yeah.
How's your dad and mom lately?
We haven't talked about anything yet.
-Oh, really?
-Yeah.
I see.
But I think it's going to be okay now.
Okay.
Tatsuki…
Thank you.
-Say that again?
-Never mind.
Tatsuki, do you have a kid?
Yeah.
You have to take good care of your family.
-Why do you say that?
-I just felt like I had to say it.
‎I see.
All right, I'm done.
Pull the paper up.
-Ta-da.
-Wow.
How is it?
-Does it look nice?
-Very nice.
Thanks.
All right.
-It's beautiful.
-So pretty.
-The orange color adds a nice accent.
-Yeah.
I'll be going now.
Bye.
Keep at it.
Thanks.
NOW ACCEPTING NEW STUDENTS
Garbage…
PREVIEW OF THE NEXT EPISODE
…will always be
nothing but garbage.
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita